Hello everyone
大家好
good afternoon
下午好
Did you get enough sleep?
有沒有睡飽了
not yet?
還沒?
Go out if you can't get enough sleep
睡不飽的再出去
wash your face and come back
洗把臉再回來可是可能要等一下等我們這一節課上完
Because each of our lecturers has prepared wonderfully
因為我們每一個講師都準備的很精彩
That environmental protection class can't talk to everyone within an hour.
那個環保課沒辦法一個小時內跟大家
Say it in detail, right?
講這麼詳細對不對
Because there's a lot of content
因為真的內容很多
I believe that everyone will see environmental protection in the future
相信大家以後看到環保的
news
新聞
It will feel special, right?
就會特別的有感覺對不對
At least I know that the waste should not be thrown around, right?
是至少知道那個廢棄物不要亂倒對不對
Really, I just heard it right, so moving
真的我剛聽到對，好感動
not sleeping
沒有在睡覺
Okay, so we're going to talk about security in this next lesson.
好那我們接下來這一堂課會講到有關安全
Fire safety if you are because you are back training?
消防安全如果你們是因為你們是回訓嗎
Then train back, I don't know if you can watch horror movies in a hurry
然後回訓我不知道你們趕不敢看恐怖影片咧
do you dare?
你們敢嗎?
Dare to watch it? Do you want to watch the one with the broken hand?
敢不敢看啊?想不想看手斷掉的那種
The one that got involved
被捲進去的那一種
It's a pity I wasn't prepared today
可是很可惜我今天沒有準備
I'll be fine next time. Next time I'm preparing for the next class.
我下一次好了下次我下一堂課在準備
Then why? Every time I have to say it, it is very bloody and terrifying, right?
那為什麼呢?每次都要講就是很很血腥很恐怖對不對
I don't have it. We're not so bloody because some people don't dare to watch
我沒有啦我們沒有那麼那麼血腥厚因為有些不人敢看
Then one is that the company has been hanging a lot recently
然後一張就是公司最近在吊掛很多
Is there a big move in the production line?
產線裡面是不是大移動
For the big mobile and then the engineers are very
對齁大移動然後工程師很辛苦啊搬這個機台每天都在申請
Okay, what are the dangers of the hanging and the moving machine?
好啦問一下大家那個吊掛還有搬運機台有什麼危害性
Is there any danger
有沒有什麼危害性
can you walk over
可以走過去嗎
can not be swayed
不可以齁
Can you watch it from the upstairs opening?
那可不可以在樓上開口的地方觀看啊
Can't
不可以
What else
還有什麼
How many people do you need for a moving table?
還有什麼搬機台的時候要幾個人
Two or more, right? You have all seen that flyer.
兩個以上對不對你們都有看到都有看到那個宣導單
But have you seen that video?
但是有看到那個影片嗎
Squeezed video
被壓到的影片
Oh, it's a pity that I didn't prepare for it today.
诶真的很可惜我今天也沒有準備
But it doesn't matter. This time, this propaganda should be quite sufficient.
不過沒有關係我們這一次這個宣導應該是蠻充足的
This is to let us know if there is a move in the field, if there is a colleague
這是告知我們如果場內如果有搬運如果有看到有同仁
Never be alone at the handling machine
在搬運機台絕對不可以只有單獨一個人
And moving cabinets
還有搬櫃子
Can't be alone
也不可以一個人喔都一樣
Because some machines have some attributes of that
因為有些機台有些那個櫃子的屬性我們其實有時候不太曉得
How is he like he might be prone to dumping so we have to be trained to move
他怎麼樣他可能容易傾倒所以我們一定要受過訓練的可以搬
Now it's all entrusted to that manufacturer
現在都是委託有那個廠商
This is the manufacturer to do the handling because they are trained
這是廠商來做搬運因為他們有受過訓練那另外一個就是如果廠內的員工在搬運的時候
Please do tell them this
請一定一定要告訴他們這個
Tips on how to move
如何搬運的技巧還有
How not to get hurt, what shoes to wear
怎麼樣才不會受傷，鞋子要穿什麼鞋
safety shoes
安全鞋
Can I wear slippers when I come to the company?
來公司可不可以穿拖鞋
No, have you ever been photographed by our people?
不可以你們有沒有被我們的人照相過
no good to you
沒有對你們都很乖
That's all right. Why don't you wear slippers to work?
這都沒有對不對為什麼不要穿拖鞋來上班
why
為什麼
not good-looking
不好看
It's not just bad looking, what else?
不是只有不好看還有什麼
I'm just afraid you'll slip when you see
就是怕你看你會滑倒
I know that if you compare convenience, you might go
我知道大家比較就是方便性的話可能要去
Is the production line right? Wear socks
產線對不對穿襪子
then wear slippers
然後穿拖鞋
It will be slippery
其實會很滑
Hope everyone can wear a comfortable shoe this should be in
希望大家可以穿一個舒適的鞋子這個應該在
The fourth class should talk about factory care related to health
第四堂課應該會講到跟健康有關的廠護
Then trouble everyone, because recently
那再麻煩大家因為最近
especially the night shift
尤其是夜班的
Especially my colleagues, please stop wearing slippers to work.
尤其是同仁請不要再穿拖鞋來上班喔
I see it will open ENC
我看到都會開ENC
Why do you need to talk about the hanging just now? Because
剛剛講吊掛的為什麼要特別講因為
We see this hanging actually
我們看到這個吊掛其實
When you see it on the road, you might still pass by on a bike, right?
你在路上看到時候你騎車可能還是會經過對不對了
You will pass but I don't dare
你會經過可是我不太敢
why
為什麼
because i think it's scary
因為我覺得這個很可怕
why is it scary
為什麼很可怕
because of
因為齁
he's not careful
他不小心喔
This is out of my control, it may be an accident
這個不是我可以控制的，這可能是意外
But we, if you are, we should have direct personnel by now
但是我們如果你是我們現在應該出了直接人員
And the engineer in that office
還有那個辦公室的工程師
Then if you are doing this kind of hair package
那如果你是在做著這類的發包
Then you have to pay special attention
那你要特別注意
Whether the manufacturer is not a qualified manufacturer
廠商沒有是不是合格廠商
And then have they done these protections in place?
然後在他們做的這些防護有沒有做到位
Then it's like this
然後就是像這個啊
This picture is the original red hat is not here
這張圖就是原本這個紅帽子沒有在這裡好
Well, our company, that's fine, that means we'll inform this
那我們公司那很好就是說我們會告知這個
red hat
紅帽子
The red hat is the overseer
紅帽子就是監工
overseer
監工
Gotta be here so if I didn't see him here it would be
一定要在這邊所以我沒有看到他在這裡的話都會
stop him he told him to be around
制止他他告訴他說一定要在附近
Make sure our employees are on the sidewalk
確保我們的員工走在人行道上
It's not okay to walk out of the warehouse. We will strictly
從倉庫走出來都是不行的我們都會嚴格制止我相信我的員工都很遵守
In addition, I would like to ask you about the escalator of
另外呢我想問一下大家那個平常百貨公司捷運高鐵站的手扶梯
Is there any harm
有沒有什麼危害
do you think there is?
有嗎你覺得有嗎
If there are too many people, will there be too few people?
人太多就有人少會不會有?
what kind of hazard
是什麼樣的危害
it's okay to think about it
想想看沒關係
what harm
什麼危害
come down
墜落
is it possible
有沒有可能
yes, yes
會啦會啦
The easiest is to get involved
最容易的是捲入
the other escalator
其他的那個手扶梯
The brush is to keep you from getting too close
毛刷他就是防止你太靠近
I'm afraid that you will be caught in that gap. Anyway, you only need your shoes or
怕那個縫隙你會被捲夾是反正你身上只要你鞋子啊或者是
Anything that can get caught in him is at risk of getting caught, so is his crevice
任何有可能被捲入的東西他就是會有捲夾的風險他的縫隙也是
That's why our MRT station told you that
所以那個我們的捷運站就有告知你說
Be careful to get involved by the edge of the ladder
物靠梯邊小心捲入
So if children wear
所以小朋友如果穿
these shoes
這種鞋子
Is he slippers?
他是拖鞋吧
It should be the slippers that have a special
應該是拖鞋就有特別的做一個警告標示告知你不要靠這個
Be careful to get involved in the edge of the ladder
梯邊小心捲入
Well, it's not that scary.
那這個也沒有很恐怖啦這個
This is what I wanted to say that day
這個就是我那一天就是想說
It doesn't seem like this
好像還沒有這個
news
新聞
I was looking for it before, and I saw that the boy's
之前找的啦就看到說這個淡水捷運站男童腳捲入手扶梯
How it got involved we don't know but
怎麼捲入的我們不知道但是
We know we don't do this unsafe action
我們知道我們不要做這種不安全的動作
Because he's naked after all
因為畢竟他就是裸露的
He's an escalator he can't cover
他就是一個手扶梯他沒有辦法覆蓋
It is actually possible to cover it, it should be possible to put that
覆蓋著其實有可能啊應該是有可能可以把那個
place to cover or what to do or what to design but for now it looks like he is
地方覆蓋住或什麼樣子做什麼樣設計但是目前看起來他是
The only way to prevent this involvement is
辦法去防止這個捲入只能
remind everyone
提醒大家
Don't go near that place, right? He still has a gap
不要靠近那個地方對不對他還是有一個縫隙
Alright, let's get to the topic
好啦我們進入主題
How can you say something like
怎麼會講到像
What about these things from the hanging pallets we saw in the company
這些東西呢從我們在公司看到的吊掛搬機台
And then on the side of the road
然後還有在路邊
On the road then there will be escalators seen in public places and what else?
路上然後會是公共場所看到的手扶梯另外還有什麼
Do you know what is the most work-related injury in our company?
你們知道我們公司那個工傷最多是什麼嗎
do you know?
你們知道嗎?
Inside or outside the factory
廠內還是廠外
Someone in the factory said it was dangerous inside the factory
廠內有人說廠內，那很危險
Why is it outside the factory?
廠外是為什麼?
What's wrong
怎麼了
ride a bike
騎車
ride a motorcycle
騎機車
bike to work
騎機車來上班
a lot really a lot
很多真的很多
Sometimes I get a stack of wounded
有時候我收到一疊受傷的
You will feel incredible, right?
你會覺得很不可思議對不對
Especially at
尤其是在
July and August
七八月
The boy was injured while riding
男生騎的受傷的所以
Slips for many reasons
很多原因啊打滑
Then the fall
然後那個自摔
some got hit
有些被撞
flash car
閃車阿
all have
都有都有
You really have to be careful when you ride your bike, especially
大家騎車真的要小心喔尤其是
drive by motorcycle
騎機車開車
These land transportation is actually a
這些陸上交通其實是我們特別要注意的一個部分
In addition, we actually have more environmental security here.
另外呢我們其實環安衛這邊大概再
After a while, I will do a little bit of off-site
過一陣子多會做一點廠外事故得這個宣導如何避免
Did you see that we have a locomotive safety campaign
你們有沒有看到我們有一個機車安全宣導
His poster was ours at the beginning, so we will do other things in the follow-up
他那個海報我們那個一開始所以後續還有再做其他
We would hope to have some courses
我們會希望有一些課程
It can be given to those colleagues who may have
可以給這些曾經也許是曾經有發生過廠外工傷的同仁
Or colleagues who are interested in this
或者是說對這個有興趣的同仁
You may be able to notice things that haven't happened while you're riding
你在騎車的時候你可能可以注意到還沒有發生的事情
is it possible
有沒有可能
you know the car ahead
你知道前面的車
He's about to hit you or if you see him he's going left to right
快要撞到你了或者是你看到他就是要往左往右
This is called defensive driving
這個叫做防禦駕駛
Defensive driving makes you predictable
防禦駕駛讓你可以預知
should you slow down
你是不是應該慢一點了
because others may
因為別人可能會
Unsafe action
有不安全動作
That's what we hope to be able to
那這個是我們希望之後可以
Hurry up to plan one
趕快規劃的一個
train
訓練
Well, it's written that the smallest family fire,
好上面寫說最小的家庭火災個人的交通意外到影響巨大
factory explosion
的工廠爆炸
Major traffic accident prevention is the establishment of safety culture
重大交通意外預防都是安全文化的建立
with continued growth
與持續的成長
what to rely on
來靠什麼
rely on me?
靠你靠我?
In fact, it depends on everyone
其實是靠大家
It's not that the general manager told you that the safety culture was established.
不是說總經理跟你說那個安全文化建立
is established, right?
就建立起來了對不對
If our colleagues see the problem and don't respond
如果我們的同任看到問題都不反應
Someday someone will fall
哪天就有人跌倒
If you saw that there were street lights on the road
如果說你看到路上原本有路燈結果燈都滅了你要不要講
Our colleagues usually speak
我們同仁一般都會講
And if you see
那還有如果看到
The machine needs to be maintained, but the power is not turned off
機台要保養的可是沒有關電
Do you dare to use it?
你敢去用嗎?
Turn off the electricity, tag and lock, we hope to be able to
關電掛牌上鎖我們希望能夠
Going deeper to push this thing out, that is, can
更深入去把這個東西推展開來也就是保養的時候能不能確實的關電
Some machines have no way but have other safety measures
有些機台沒有辦法但是有其他的安全措施
We know there are other safety measures but
我們知道有其他安全措施但是
Turning off the electricity, tagging and locking is the most
關電掛牌上鎖是最
A security measure that will not be missed
不會有疏漏的一個安全措施
The other is to say
那另外的就是說
this culture
這個文化
I believe our colleagues have heard
我相信我們同仁都聽過了
Stop and Fix
Stop and Fix
Have heard of Stop and Fixp
都聽過Stop and Fixp
The company uses these Slogans
公司就是用這些Slogan
And like our ATQM
還有像是我們的ATQM
There is a lot of quality here
品質的這邊有很多的
These activities make our colleagues really start from the grassroots level
這些活動都讓我們的同仁很其實是從基層開始
a lot of participation
很多的參與
The security guard here is
那環安衛這邊就是
Hope to have your participation
希望有各位的參與
Did you find any problems
你們有發現任何的問題
be sure to return
一定要回報
must speak
一定要講
come and ask you this comic
來我問你這個漫畫
the first is
第一個是
There's a place where it's about to break
有一個快要斷裂的地方
The hook is a little loose
吊鉤那邊有點鬆脫
Or about to break
或者是快要斷裂損壞
This is an unsafe
這個是一個不安全的
environment
環境
Then there's someone walking downstairs without a helmet
再來有人走在底下沒戴安全帽
someone walks underneath
有人走在底下
It's an unsafe act to just walk past
剛好可以過就走過去這個是一個不安全的行為
unsafe behavior
不安全的行為
incomplete action
不完全的動作
The third one fell off
第三格這個東西掉下來了
Did you get hit in front of them?
在他們的面前有沒有砸到
No
沒有
It doesn't matter if it doesn't hit them, they'll just go to the surprise.
沒有砸到沒關係他們就去收驚就好
It's called Near Miss, what we call a false alarm.
這叫做Near Miss 就是我們說的虛驚事故
Okay, come again, okay next time someone walks by
好來再來好下次又有人走過去了
second third fourth fourth
第二個第三個第四個
Okay maybe lucky to get to the 300th
好也許很幸運到第三百個
301 was hit
301就被砸到了
this is
這個就
I don't know if I go to heaven or hell
上天堂或下地獄也不知道
It was an accident so we have
這是一個意外事故所以我們有
With maybe 300 false alarms, he could cause a serious accident
可能有300個虛驚事故的時候他可能就會造成一個很嚴重的意外
What is a false alarm
什麼叫做虛驚事故
Because we often go to the production line
因為我們常常去產線的時候
You may have seen someone hit by the
可能有看到有人被機台打到，很多小問題沒有很嚴重
Someone next to me will say that I was like that at the time.
旁邊就會有人說我當時也這樣啊
I was hit by that thing last time too.
我上次也被那個東西打到阿
We asked him why no one told us?
我們問他為什麼都沒有人告訴我們?
will you speak
你們會不會講
Do you need to tell the foreman if you cut your hand and use the OK jump?
手割到了用一下OK蹦需要跟領班說嗎?
usual tool
平常在的工具
accidentally let you
不小心讓你
let you
讓你
Maybe you were good at first, but you didn't cut it that day.
可能你原本很順手啊你那一天就不順手割到了
smashed, smashed
砸到了砸傷了
If you suffer a little injury, hurry up and
受了點小傷趕快包一包繼續工作不要講
These false alarms we hope
這些虛驚事故我們希望
From
從
start this year
今年開始
Colleagues can be brave
同仁可以勇於
to say this happened
去說這個曾經發生過
Such a thing
這樣的事情
Because the false alarm story has to be improved
因為虛驚事故事必須要去改善的
Our original first aid kit
我們原本的急救箱
I put OK jump in the first aid kit, where is it now?
急救箱裡面放OK蹦，現在放在哪裡?
Now put the stairs
現在放樓梯口
put a lot before
之前放很多
less now
現在放比較少
First aid kits are scarce
急救箱比較少
I want to say why everyone gets hurt, every day someone gets hurt
想說怎麼大家都受傷，每天都有人受傷
Every day someone takes OK to jump
每天都有人拿OK蹦
I don't know what was hurt
受什麼傷都不知道
So we hope
所以我們希望
Learn what our employees look like from these managements
從這些管理當中了解說我們的員工是什麼樣子的
under action
動作下
at work
工作上
will have these
會有這些
Small injury, let's go to explain from
小傷我們進而再從去了解說
Is there any room for improvement? In fact, we have found some points for improvement.
有沒有去改善的地方好在這裡面其實我們是有找到一些改善的點喔
There was a colleague who was
原本有同仁是
It's normal for him to cut his hands easily when doing certain jobs
在做某一些的工作的時候他手很容易割手覺得很正常
it's normal
就很正常
That's how his hands are
那就手就這樣子啊他
He thought the glove might be useless
他覺得那個手套可能沒有什麼用
But after we got to know it, I was very responsible as the
可是我們去了解之後還有當我們部門的環安衛委員很盡責
who will find out who
去了解之後就會發現誰
what kind of protective gear they can use
他們可以使用什麼樣的防護具
Cut-resistant gloves to help them so they won't be cutting
防割傷手套去幫助他們那就不會在割傷了
cuts are not normal
割傷不是正常
those are not normal
那些都不是正常
So we learn from these questions like this that we hope that our colleagues
所以我們從這樣子這樣子的這些問題當中去了解我們希望同仁
If you are a direct employee, you can use e-ID or union
如果你是直接人員可以透過e-ID或是工會
reflect these recommendations
反映這些建議
In addition,
另外就是
Through the supervisor and the environmental safety and health committee
透過主管領班還有環安衛委員
If the environmental safety and health committee
環安衛委員要是不知道是誰可以問領班
you, if you are
你們啊如果是在
You can find it directly on the production line
產線那邊可以直接找
Find that foreman like this
找那個領班這樣子
then or
然後或者是說
you have some special
你們有一些比較特殊的
Safety, health and environmental protection issues
安全健康環保問題
You want to tell the environmental security personnel
你們想要直接告訴環安衛的人員說也可以拿來給你們一個管道
There is a poster of us in our warehouse
就是在我們的倉庫有貼一張我們的海報
what about this poster
這個海報呢
tell you
告訴你說
If there are environmental health and safety issues that have not been resolved
如果有環保健康安全問題沒有解決
what is not resolved
什麼是沒有解決
Do you think it's been said many times?
你覺得講了很多次啊
I don't seem to know when to improve
好像不太知道什麼時候改善
You want to tell us through a channel like this
你想要透過這樣子的管道來告訴我們
You can directly scan the QRcode and fill in it
可以直接掃描QRcode在上面填寫
When filling out, you still need to
填寫的時候還是要
Fill in your real name and phone number and let us know
填上你的真實姓名和電話讓我們知道
What do we do we have to tell you, for example, we will tell you
我們做了什麼事情我們要告訴你啊例如說我們會告知你說
We're going to see it live or say what we do to improve
我們要去現場看或者說我們做什麼改善
Then I will communicate with you first
然後會先跟你溝通了解
so
所以
You can use this pipe next to the union
大家可以利用這個管道在工會的旁邊
The wall next to the milk collection room has this pipe on the dining room side.
集乳室旁邊的那個牆就是在餐廳那邊都有這個管道
That or as you say a lot right?
那或者像你講很多的對不對
Foreman of Environmental Safety and Health Committee
環安衛委員領班主管
In fact, anyone can report
其實任何人都可以通報
come again
來再來
Well, we just happened to mention that another restaurant has a phone
那我們剛剛好有提到另外一個餐廳有一個電話
This is also the phone number if you don't
這個電話也是如果有什麼事情你手上剛好沒有公司的電話
In need of emergency contact there is a phone
需要緊急聯絡在餐廳的素食區有一個電話
This call isn't for you to order a drink, it's for you
這電話不是讓你叫飲料的喔是要讓你
If it's really an emergency, use this phone and there will be
打電話如果真的是緊急的狀況用這支電話然後上面會有
The guard room also has an extension for our factory affairs.
警衛室還有我們廠務的分機
ok and then again
好喔然後再來就是
Because I just talked about home safety
因為剛剛有講到說居家安全
you come to work you are from home
你來上班你是從家裡
We should all be safe when we go home after work at the company.
到公司工作完回家我們是都要平安啊
happy
開開心心
then go home
然後回家
Then it's the same at home. We have to celebrate the Spring
然後在家裡一樣啊都要過春節對我們希望同仁都在家裡都過得
You can relax and come back
可以身心舒暢然後再來
Refresh and go to work, right?
恢復精神來上班對不對
Then let's take a look
那我們看一下
fire this piece
消防這塊
I won't talk about the company in particular here
我這裡不會特別講到有關公司
a situation of
的一個狀況但是我會從
In terms of home fire prevention, because of this we
居家的火災的預防來講因為這個我們
It was not mentioned in the previous
在以前的那個環安衛課程比較沒有提到
That hope he can be prevented from this home fire
那希望他可以從這個居家的火災的預防
to recognize and to understand
可以去認識到並且去了解到說
how to identify and
怎麼樣子去辨識並且
Know more about these little knowledge about the prevention of this fire
更知道說這個火災的預防的這些小小的知識
Let's take a look. In fact, electrical appliances
來看一下齁那其實電器現在用電器很多對不對
There are people who use mobile phones and tablets, many small appliances, and so on.
用手機用平板啊很多小家電啊都有人所以
In fact, the first is the electrical fire
其實第一名就是電氣火災
good to see a picture
好來看一張圖片
The storage of this fan
這個電風扇的收納
we're gonna take this
我們要把這個
The wires must be tied up, right?
電線一定要把他捆好對不對
Is that safe?
那這樣子是安全的嗎
is this safe
這樣是安全的嗎
Is this neat but safer?
這樣是整齊的可是較安全嗎
think about it
想一下
The extension cord you just bought will actually bundle it up for you.
剛買回來的延長線其實會幫你捆好
sell
販賣
ok that's neat
好那就是很整齊
But is this arrangement safe?
可是這樣子的整理方式是安全的嗎?
Just think about it, right?
一樣要想一下對不對
Well, that's actually because when I was a kid
好那其實從因為小時候
When I was a child, my mother would tell us
小時候媽媽就會跟我們講
You'll see a lot of people tying him up like this
你會看到很多人會把他這樣綑一綑捲一捲
Because it's neater
因為這樣比較整齊
good but
好可是
But it's not really safe
可是可是這樣子真的不是真的安全
watch a video
看一個影片喔
Many fire scenes are caused by extension cords
許多火災現場都是延長線惹的禍
Some are plugging too many electrical appliances at one time and overloading
有的是一次插太多電器超過負荷
Some people forget to turn off the power supply and the wires go off.
有的是電源忘了關電線走火
However, a man surnamed Wang in New Taipei City
不過新北市一名王姓男子
Suspected that the extension cord was
疑似是關了延長線電源但還是釀成火警
At that time, the man surnamed Wang plugged the electric fan into the extension
當時王姓男子將電風扇插在延長線上沒想到出門後延長線引發大火
The woman surnamed Huang who lives on the 11th floor
住在11樓的黃姓婦人
Let's listen again I've just been
我們重聽一下我剛剛一直
I didn't enlarge him, wait a minute
沒有把他把他放大等一下喔
Many fire scenes are caused by extension cords
許多火災現場都是延長線惹的禍
Some are plugging too many electrical appliances at one time and overloading
有的是一次插太多電器超過負荷
Some people forget to turn off the power supply and the wires go off.
有的是電源忘了關電線走火
However, a man surnamed Wang in New Taipei City was suspected to have turned
不過新北市一名王姓男子疑似是關了延長線電源但還是釀成火警
At that time, the man surnamed Wang plugged the electric fan into the extension cord
當時王姓男子將電風扇插在延長線上
Unexpectedly, the extension line caused a fire after going out
沒想到出門後延長線引發大火住在11樓的黃姓婦人逃生時被嗆運送醫不治
The man surnamed Wang uses an extension cord
王姓男子在房間內使用的就是像這樣子有獨立開關延長線
But he said he had an electric fan at the time
但他說他當時電風扇
Does your extension cord look like this?
你們家的那個延長線是不是長這個樣子
right
對齁
Ah, does your family have anything attached to it?
啊你們家的有沒有那個什麼過附載
will automatically jump
會自動跳脫
That one is more expensive, but there is this independent switch, right?
那個比較貴但是有這個獨立開關對不對
That's the same thing they use, our family also uses this
那個他們用的一樣我們家也是用這個
take a look
去看一下
is not running
是沒有運行的
And the switch is also off
而且開關也是關閉的
He therefore thinks that there has been no negligence in his use
因此他認為他的使用上面沒有出疏失
The man surnamed Wang told the prosecution that his extension line had been used
王姓男子向檢方表示他的延長線使用不到7個月的時間而且延長線有通過安全檢驗
There is also an overload automatic power-off protection mechanism
也有過載自動斷電保護機制
There is also an independent switch on the socket, and
插座上也有獨立開關當時只差上了一個電風扇
However, after inspection, the police confirmed that the
不過警方看驗後確認為延長線只要連接在牆壁插座上
power-on state
就屬於通電狀態
It is believed that the man surnamed Wang did not notice that the extension
認為王姓男子沒有註意到延長線有破損而釀禍依照過失致死罪判刑
Is this serious?
這樣有沒有很嚴重啊
If you have not unplugged the extension cord at home
你們如果家裡的延長線沒有拔
and then cause someone else's
然後呢造成別人的
It should be said that someone else died at home
應該說別人家裡死亡
This will still be sentenced. Of course, this can still be appealed.
這還是會被判刑的當然這個還是可以上訴這裡所說的就是說他說沒有拔掉要延長線
In addition, the power-on state
另外就是通電狀態
and then again
然後再來就是
The plastic outer film is deteriorating so like you have checked at home
塑膠外膜劣化所以像你們有在家裡檢查
Do you have an extension cord in your house?
你們家裡面的延長線嗎
Someone will check I think it's great
有人會檢查我覺得很棒
Especially the ones behind the cabinets
尤其是櫃子後面的
pressed for a long time
壓了很久
right
對不對
I don't know what he looks like now, right?
已經不知道他現在長什麼樣子了對不對
maybe even that
可能連那個
I don't know where the socket is
插座在哪裡都不知道
Is there such a pair
有沒有這種對
because you lived for a long time?
因為住很久了嗎
I watched a video the other day, it is not convenient to put that video here
我那天看了一個影片這裡不太方便放那個影片
It's just that there's a video, he's directly
就是就是有一個影片喔他就是直接在就是
Measured above
上面實測
Test this extension cord
實測這個延長線
little
小小小
what card is it small?
小什麼牌嗎
Or some Taiwan-made or
或者是說某一些台灣製的或者是
general traditional
一般傳統的
Extension cord
延長線
That's actually
那其實
he will advertise
他會標榜說
Overload he will jump
過載他會跳脫
Or maybe he's going to advertise a lot of things but he doesn't have to be
或者是他會標榜很多的一些東西但是他不是一定真的這樣
So after passing through, some people may take it
所以在經過可能有些人會去把它拆掉來看一看是不是真的像他講的
That's probably not true
一樣那也許不是真的這樣
So something like what we bought back is good especially
所以像我們買回來的東西好尤其是
this extension cord if you
這個延長線那如果你
leave home
離開家裡
Maybe it will take a long time to go out, or we can promote it
可能出門會比較久或者是我們在公司裡面辦公室宣導一下就是如果春節的時候
Before the Spring Festival, please send your
春節之前辦公室人員請把你們的
extension cord
延長線都
unplugged
插頭都拔掉
be sure to unplug
一定要拔掉
At that time, there may be another propaganda such as this
到時候可能會再發一個宣導這樣
Then if you have such a habit in your home, this is the establishment of a safety
那如果家裡面你有這樣的習慣這就是安全文化的建立全家都知道出門要拔插頭
This is important because you really don't know if it's like this, right?
這個很重要因為你真的不曉得是不是像這個狀況對不對
Don't you take care of it every day?
你不會每天都要保養嗎
Do you have
有沒有
ah no
啊不會啊
Let's go to the next one
我們來看下一個
Ask everyone, which one of these four electrical appliances
問大家一下請問一下這四個電器你覺得哪一個比較容易會有電氣火災
On the left is the heater
左上是電暖器
what is the top right
右上是什麼
Cool, what else?
冷氣啊然後還有什麼
electric fan
電風扇
dehumidifier
除濕機
which one do you think
你覺得是哪一個
easier to happen
比較容易發生
Do you think the frequency is high?
那你們覺得頻率高的咧
still the same
還是一樣是
electric heater
電暖器嗎
do you often use electric heaters
你常在用電暖器嗎
It may not be used in winter
冬天也不一定會拿出來用
So which one is the most commonly used
所以最常用的是哪一個
Electric fans are most commonly used for electric fans,
電風扇對電風扇最常用的是電風扇的頻率還比較高
So actually the fan is really
所以其實電風扇還真的是
Give him regular maintenance because he gets dust stuck on it
定期要給他保養一下因為他會有灰塵卡在上面
Then if he doesn't move, then you keep giving him
然後他如果不動的時候然後你又一直給他
He's been on the power all the time, he might just suddenly
他就一直在通電他可能就突然就怎樣
Otherwise it will catch fire
不然就是著火了
really catch fire
真的會著火
So like this we usually
所以說像這個我們平常
There are a lot of commonly used electrical appliances in the home to pay attention to
家裡常用電器很多要注意
Why is this course designed like this because we are often watching the news
為什麼這個課程要設計成這樣因為我們常常在看新聞
Lots of fires in that house
很多的那個住宅的火災
You won't know why this fire happened
你是不會知道為什麼會有這個火災的
You won't know because he won't tell you
你不會知道因為他都不會告訴你
In fact, many of the
那其實很多的都是從
from these appliances
從這些家電來的
you may not imagine
你可能想像不到
Then we hope that all of you colleagues have this knowledge
那我們希望你們同仁在上過這一輪的那個回訓大家都有這個知識
Let's take a look at the fouling conductive
來看一下積汙導電
Put the cotton on the plug first and then into the socket
先將棉花放在插頭上然後再插入插座
Create a dusty state between the iron plug and the socket
使鐵插頭和插座之間產生有灰塵的狀態
pouring water
在注水
After a while, white smoke appeared directly from the plug and socket
不久之後插頭和插座直接出現了白煙
The flame is more than 20 cm high
火焰高達20公分以上
The plug is completely burnt
插頭完全燒焦
temperature up to mild
溫度高達輕度
The last time I saw a case, he said that the socket behind the cabinet caught fire.
上次看到一個案例他就是講說櫃子櫃子後面的那個插座起火
Is he just because it's been useless for too long?
他就是因為太久沒有用嗎
Then he easily accumulates this dust
然後他很容易積這個灰塵
On January 8th, I know you guys are you going to work?
1月8號我知道你們你們有上上班嗎
Are you home without work?
沒有上班都在家嗎
What are the factories and manufacturers doing here?
那廠務部還有廠商來這裡幹嘛
What's up on January 8th?
1月8號是做什麼嗎
Power outage and then the last two words are very important, not just power outages
停電然後來後面兩個字很重要不是只有停電喔
blackout what
停電什麼
Power outage maintenance
停電保養
do what
做什麼
put that dust
把那些灰塵
Sweep the dust out of the cabinets in the substation
變電站裡面那些櫃子灰塵掃一掃
clear it all
全部都把它清清除掉
Do it once a year and that's it, so how about you at home?
每年要做一次就是這樣子所以你在家裡啊也是怎麼樣
It's not just about cleaning the floor
掃一掃把清潔一下不是只有清那個地板
May be in this kind of appliance, especially if you
可能在這種電器尤其是你可能那個插座拉或者是那個延長線放在
It's been too long for a place you might want to clean it up wait
某個地方太久了你可能要給他清潔一下等一下講到另外一個東西也是需要清潔
We just talked about why not to bind
我們剛講為什麼不要綑綁
Something will happen to this bundle
這個綑綁就會出事情
Bundle the wires together as you did before
把電線捆在一起和剛才的做法一樣
turn the power on
將電源打開
After 3 minutes, white smoke started to come out of the socket
3分鐘後插座處開始冒出白煙
After another 30 seconds
又經過30秒後
Fire occurs in the wire
電線發生走火現象
Measure with a thermometer
此時以溫度計來測量
Will find bundled wires up to 150 degrees
會發現經過綑綁的電線高達150度
The picture is very clear, right?
這個圖很清楚對不對
The bundled wire above is 100 degrees, if you are at home
上面那個綑綁的電線是100度啦你如果你在家裡
But find an open space
可是要找個空曠地方
Also need a thermal imager
還要熱像儀來側
Is it true that he will be over 100 degrees
是真的會這樣子他會超過100度
It says 150 degrees on it, next time you look at it
上面是寫150度啊下次你看
You can tell what the difference is by looking at it, so
看就知道說他的差別在哪裡所以家裡的電線真的不要綑綁然後那個吹風機
Because of his high power and then he finds out that the appliance is hot right?
因為他高功率然後他才會發現那個電器很熱對不對
absolutely not bound
絕對不可以綑綁
This whole family has a sense of safety
這個全家都有安全意識
Say don't tie, don't tie
說不要捆不要綁
ok then don't bend
好然後不要彎折
Can't be folded, can't be tied, what should I do?
不可以折可不可以綁那怎麼辦
Then it's ok to collect it in large rolls
那就大捲的去收是ok的
Also, what is overloading?
另外我們來講什麼是過載
I just mentioned that the overload switch will trip
剛有講到說過載開關會跳
If it is overloaded, it will jump
過載的話都跳脫
how to calculate
怎麼算
This simple calculation
這個簡單的計算題喔
When the current flowing through the wire exceeds the safe capacity
流經電線的電流超過安全容量時
If the overload protection switch fails, there is no action
若過載保護開關失效無動作的話
The high temperature generated by the overcurrent will cause the insulation
過電流產生高溫會使電線外表的絕緣物燒熔碳化甚至引起燃燒
Have you noticed that the extension cord is always full of plugs?
大家是否有註意延長線上總是插滿了插頭
Is the extension cord overloaded?
這樣延長線是否負荷過重呢
Let me explain to you how to calculate if an extension cord is overloaded
讓我來跟大家說明一下如何計算延長線是否有過載的情形
If the extension cord load is 15 amps
假如延長線負荷量為15安培
Three electrical appliances plugged into an
三個電器同時插在一個延長線上分別為電子鍋
His power consumption is 880 watts
他的耗電功率是880瓦特
Micro-wave oven
微波爐
750 watt thermos is 110 watt
750瓦特兒熱水瓶則是110瓦特
Electric pot consumes 880 watts of power
電子鍋耗電功率為880瓦
What is the voltage that is usually used at home?
家裡待用的平常在用的電壓是多少
110 is right, if you have a pen, divide 750 by 100
110對不對有筆的算一下750除以100
And how much does 880 divided by 110 add up?
還有一個880除以110加起來多少
so there is no more than 15 amps
這樣有沒有超過15安培
yes or no
有對不對
If this is exceeded, it is called overload.
這樣已超過就是叫過載了
Therefore, there are many extension cord sockets outside. There are
所以外面的延長線插座很多有六個，八個，三個都有他是全部插滿叫過載
yes
是嗎
After this class, you'll know it's not
上完這堂課就知道不是了
But you have to calculate the power to use this appliance and divide it by your usual
而是你要去計算以使用這個電器的功率要除與他除於你平常
Does the 110 add up to exceed the load of the
110加起來有沒有超過上面延長線的負荷量通常就是15安培
Okay, or you can usually pay attention to whether
好或者是你平常也可以去注意 一下你們家延長線目前有沒有很
It's very hot, you can't continue to use it like this, you have to buy it again
很燙就不可以再繼續用這樣子你可要再買那種
better his
再好一點的他的那個
The extension cord is thicker.
那個延長線比較粗一點的
this is
這個是
small calculations
小小的計算
I believe everyone will
相信大家都會
Well, let's take a look at a very simple promotional video.
好接下來看一下一個很簡單的宣導影片
This is your exam
這個是你們的考試有
What happened
發生什麼事了
It's really convenient to have an extension cord
有延長線真方便
Can use a lot of appliances at the same time
可以同時用好多的電器喔
Blow your hair while the hot water is boiling
煮熱水的時候先來吹頭髮好了
wonder what it tastes like
奇怪這是什麼味道
What happened
發生什麼事了
Electrical fires cannot be extinguished with water
電器火災不能用水滅火
Be sure to use a dry powder fire extinguisher
一定要用乾粉滅火器
Remember the following principles
謹記以下原則
Do not overload
用電不得超載
Wires are not bundled
電線不綑綁
The plug is not wet and dirty
插頭不潮溼汙損
Unplug electrical appliances when not in use
不使用電器時請拔掉插頭
Do not put combustibles around the appliance
電器周圍不放可燃物
Do not buy and do not use electrical appliances without safety labels
沒有安全標章的電氣不買不用
Watch out for signs of electrical fire
注意電器火災的前兆
lights dimmed
電燈變暗
Bulbs burn out frequently
燈泡經常燒毀
hot wire
發熱的電線
smell of burning wires
聞到電線燃燒的味道
Switchboards often trip without fuses
配電盤經常出現無熔絲開關跳脫
so that
所以說那個
What are our exam answers
我們的考試答案是什麼
Are our exams on the above?
我們的考試是考上面幾個嗎
So what's the harbinger of something when this comes up?
所以這出現的時候是什麼什麼的前兆
Symptoms of an electrical fire
電氣火災的前兆
Let's take a look again, time is running out
我們再來趕快看一下時間不多了
This attention is to remember not to accumulate dust,
這個註意啊就是記住不要積灰塵不要擠壓不要綑綁不要過載
then use
然後使用
Safety label products must have at least this is the minimum standard
安全標章產品至少要有啦這個是最低標準
say if you are
說如果你有在
Group purchases must pay attention to buying electrical appliances
群組團購購買電器用品一定要注意
Be sure to pay attention to the best brands
一定要注意最好是大的廠牌喔
Did we test this? You write so seriously
我們有考這個嗎你寫那麼認真
Remember that we have seen a lot of videos just now,
記得剛剛我們已經有看到很多影片了對不對然後看到一些說明了告訴你
You go home today just to pay attention
你回家今天回家就是要注意一下
especially during the Spring Festival
尤其是春節期
clean up before
之前要大掃除
Check the plug at home
家裡插頭看一下
Extension cord
延長線
If you want to replace it, just replace it, okay?
要換的就更換一下好不好
So don't collect dust, don't squeeze, don't bundle, don't overload
所以不要積灰塵不要擠壓不要綑綁不要過載
Don't be overloaded
不要過載怎麼算
remember
記得嗎
Divide that voltage by 110 pairs
除以那個電壓110對
I'll take a look at home
我回家看一下啊不知道怎麼看的再問我
your home plug
你們家的插頭
It will be hot to the touch
摸下去會燙的齁
Look at the water and electricity, this is a precursor
那個水電來看一下這個都是前兆
blackened is worse
發黑的更糟
It's the same when we just talked about the maintenance of electrical appliances
一樣啊我們剛講那個電器保養的時候
Manufacturers will also come to see these in our company
廠商也是會來看我們公司裡面這些
Are the wires in the substation black?
變電站裡面的電線有沒有發黑
Hurry up, we may skip this first, let's watch this video, it's the power bank
趕快我們這個可能先跳過我們看一下這個影片好了就是行動電源
Although the fire was extinguished, the remaining smoke continued to escape
儘管火滅了但殘存的煙還是不斷從三樓竄出凌晨3點多新北市蘆洲光華路
The man in the apartment house was on fire, and the man's
公寓民宅竄火苗屋內男子手被燒著通到驚醒才發現起火了
The computer starts to burn
電腦那邊開始燒起來
So what time did he catch the fire?
所以他是什麼時間點火災的
Sleep versus sleep is usually the case so don't sleep
睡覺對睡覺的時候通常都是這樣所以睡覺的時候不要
Charge that is what to charge
充那是要充電的東西
Don't go to charge from that thing while sleeping and then
睡覺的時候不要去從那個充電的東西然後
put some combustibles
旁邊放一些可燃物
look further down
再往下看
this is
這個是
Everyone should not know about this news that happened before.
之前發生的這個新聞應該大家都不知道
Come to care about what happened yesterday morning
來關心發生在昨天上午台北林森北路的錢櫃KTV
Fire accident killed 5 people, more than 50 injured and sent to hospital
火警事件造成5人不幸死亡50多個人受傷送醫
What's the cause of the fire? The police have an update today
起火的原因是什麼呢檢警今天有最新的進展了
The monitor screen on the 5th floor of the KTV building was exposed
這ktv大樓5樓的監視器畫面曝光
At 9:07 a.m., a foreman surnamed Wang who
在上午9點07分的時候 一名當時正在施作大樓電梯工程的王姓工頭
He holds a laser rangefinder in his hand
他手拿著一個雷射測距儀
Go into the storage room to charge the battery of this rangefinder
進到儲藏室來幫這個測距儀的電池充電
After 105 minutes, it is 10:52 in the morning
隔了105分鐘後也就是上午的10點52分
Surveillance footage captured the fire coming out of the storage room
監視器畫面拍到了儲藏室冒出了火光
Then it started to burn
接著開始起火燃燒
The police rescued the foreman Wang surnamed today and transferred him to the
警方今天緊急救約談的這位王姓工頭 並且將他依照過失致死還有公共危險的罪嫌移送地檢署複訊
The latest news after the news is that he pays 100,000 yuan on bail
訊後最新消息是他以10萬元交保
And restricting the outbound and sea also restricts the footprint
並且限制出境出海也限制足跡
The man in black walked around with the wires
黑衣男子拿著電線走來走去然後折返儲藏室
Open the curtains, bend over and squat down to charge
打開簾子彎下腰蹲下去充電
No one came in or out during the work in the construction area
再回頭施工區工作期間沒有人進出
Shortly afterward the storage room was on fire
不久之後儲藏室冒出火光
Then the fire got bigger and bigger
接著火勢越來越大火警發生後
It's not a few minutes
這沒有幾分鐘的時間
He just took something like an instrument
他只是拿一個像儀器的東西
We most often use a thing called a vacuum cleaner in the production line
我們在產線裡面最常會用到一個東西叫做吸塵器
that needs charging
那個是需要充電的
what else to charge
還有什麼要充電
wireless
無線的
the wireless one
無線的那個
Everything you will use at home needs to be charged like a cell phone
你家裡會用到的東西都一樣要充電像手機
These are all to be charged. In the production
這些都是要充電的我們在產線裡面我們會要求大家要定位
It's the battery charger that gives you a place
竟是電池充電器給大家一個位置
At this location, he needs CCTV surveillance
這個位置他要有CCTV監視或是要有人你們常常經過的地方
Then there can be no combustibles within two meters
然後兩公尺內不可以有可燃物因為他如果燒起來的話他不會延燒到旁邊
So this is the rule of the line
所以這是產線的規定
The other one is
那另外一個就是
That is to say, the battery
就是說這個離電池
take a quick look
快速看一下
Use lithium batteries
使用鋰電池
Something to watch out for, especially now
要注意的地方尤其是現在
A lot of things that use power banks
很多用行動電源那一些東西
that if
那如果是
If you don't know where you came from, he may spontaneously
來路不明的他有可能會自燃就是你放在那邊包包他就自己就乾燒了
This is actually
這個其實都
many cases
很多案例了
Pay special attention to his mark when buying these
購買這些都要特別注意他的標章
Do not put in high temperature in summer
不要放在高溫的地方夏天的時候
Let's take a look at how to minimize disasters. If
再來我們看一下如何將災害降到最低如果因為我們今天特別在講居家的防火
It should be said that in addition to pulling the plug just mentioned, this is a
應該是說除了剛講的拔插頭這個是一個
there are other
有其他的
how to lower
要怎麼樣降低
In fact, the fire department of the Ministry of the
內政部消防署他們在今年的對策其實他上面就有寫了
First
第一個
Promote the use of extension cords with overload protection devices
宣導使用加裝過負載保護裝置延長線
To CNS check the combination and come to the second one
要CNS檢驗合再來第二個
If your family has lived for more than 20 years, he specially wrote this
你們家如果真的是住了20年以上他特別寫這樣
assist in advocacy
協助宣導
People have used indoor wiring for more than 20 years at home
民眾居家使用20年以上室內配線
Please invite qualified electrical contractors to update
委請合格電器承裝業者於以更新喔
No subsidy seems useless
沒有補助好像沒有用
Because some really lived for a long time, this is true, I
因為有些真的是住很久啦這個這個是真的我看到所以滿訝異他沒有要補助
The next one is to put on the siren because it is
下一個就是裝住警器因為它是
predictable
可以預報的
When there is a fire, let me know to escape quickly
有火災的時候讓我知道趕快逃生的
Does the company have the so-called function like this alarm device?
公司有沒有那個所謂像這個住警器一樣功能
it's over without us
沒有我們就完了
It's bad if you don't have it, we have it, have you seen that white one?
沒有就糟了，我們有啦，有沒有看到那個白白的
This smoke detector will be installed in the company
公司裡面就會裝這個偵煙器
the white one
白色那一顆
You didn't find that he ever had a false positive
你沒有發現他曾經有誤報過
there is absolutely
有絕對有
do you know
知道嗎
It's not that we play with fire, it's not the
不是我們玩火耶不是產線有人當然不是
He will be like what he just said
他一樣是會像剛剛講的
he might collect dust
他有可能會積灰塵
he might misreport
他就有可能會誤報
Yeah, let's go back to the one we're looking at now
對啊我們回到我們現在看的這一張喔
Therefore, if your home is a Toutian apartment
所以透天你們家如果是透天公寓或是平房反正就是不是大樓
The building will do it for you, right?
大樓會幫你們裝對不對
There will be one that is managed as a whole, but if your
會有一個就是整體管理的但是如果說你們家不是你們是住透天租公寓或是你去
Rent an old house, he is in the sky, etc.
租老房子他是在透天裡面的等等
It's better to ask everyone to install this so-called police station
就是最好請大家裝這個所謂的住警器
like this one
就像這一顆
And then live the police, in fact, he has two types
然後住警器那其實他他有分兩種
1 is the smoke detection type
1種就是偵煙式
Tobacco detection is just as the name implies, it will sound when there is smoke.
偵煙就是顧名思義就是有煙他會響啊
The second constant temperature
第二個定溫式
Let everyone wake up quickly
讓大家趕快清醒下
Where
什麼地方
Where is your home you need to install a thermostat
你們家什麼地方你就要裝定溫式
The kitchen, wow 100 points
廚房，哇100分
Buddha hall, yes, there will be smoke
佛堂，對，會有煙的
That place will be installed with a thermostat
那個地方就要裝定溫式
There will be two options
會有這兩種可以選
Then I have to recognize this safety mark. He
然後再來要認可這個安全標章他還是有安全標章有經過檢驗的
which places
哪些地方
The kitchen is equipped with constant
廚房裝定溫式樓梯走廊還有寢室這些都要裝
why
為什麼
Because you don't know where the fire is
因為你不知道哪個地方在起火啊
As soon as he's on fire, he rings, and you'll know where it is
他只要起火了他響了你就知道是哪一個地方
The way he installs is very convenient, but if it is sticky foam, it may fall off.
他裝的方式很方便好可是如果是黏泡棉的話有可能會掉喔
I have experience with this so I know it might fall off
這個我有經驗所以我知道可能會掉
But it's a simple and simple type and you have
但是他是簡易的簡易型另外你要定期測試然後再來擦拭清潔
Because he just said that he may have misreported
因為剛剛講他有可能會誤報
Let's see what's going on
我們看一下到底是會講什麼
The quiz has a flame and immediately emits a 90 decibel broadcast plus a red light
測驗有火焰立刻發出90分貝廣播加紅燈
siren
警報器
The key to life-saving when a fire occurs, but how to install it is very important
火警發生時的保命關鍵但怎麼裝很重要
The idea of ​​the fool-proof device boils down to plug it in first anyway
防呆裝置念歸結反正先插著
Then when we operate, I will first test whether it is normal.
那在我們操作的時候我會先測試一下他是不是正常
The test is normal, it means the power is on
測試正常代表電源有通
Behind him is just that double-sided tape
他後面只是一個那個雙面膠
can
就可以
stuck
黏住了
When installing alarm aids, be sure to keep them away from air-conditioning outlets
安裝助警器要注意一定要遠離冷氣的出風口
Or at least 1.5 meters above the ceiling fan and choose a sturdy place to install
或者是吊扇附近至少1.5米以上而且要選個堅固的地方來安裝
The alarm is very easy to install
住警器安裝相當方便
A 500 to 800 yuan plasma battery can be used for 10 years
一個500到800元不等離電池可用10年
You know what he's like if you stick to it, you'll get hit by him
你知道嗎像他這樣如果你是用黏得你會被他打到
really fall
真的會掉下來
It's true. I just said that the foam is right because my house fell off.
是真的剛講說泡棉對不對因為我家的就掉了
It's scary, I'm afraid of falling and hitting my head
很恐怖，怕掉下來砸到頭
Pay attention to where you put it
裝的地方要注意然後
If it is installed, it should be sturdy
如果是裝上面要堅固
He has to be strong
他要很堅固
I'm done with this one
那這一個我講完了
So again calling to fill up and then another one is specifically mentioned here
所以再次呼籲裝好裝滿然後另外一個這裡有特別講到說
Reserve more than two escape exits
預留兩個以上的逃生出口
do we have two here
我們這裡有沒有兩個
Yes, there are two, we can go from this way over there.
有啦算是有兩個，那邊雜物我們可以從這邊走
Go to that many places to sing and eat outside
去那個外面唱歌吃飯很多地方
What should be paid attention to when staying in hotels
公共場所飯店住宿要注意的就是有沒有兩個逃生出口
Pay attention to that when you go
去的時候先注意一下那個
Is there any clearance for the escape ladder?
逃生梯有沒有淨空
Then I will tell you more about the company
然後另外再跟大家講一下公司裡面的
these escape ladders
這些逃生梯
You can't put anything on the stairs.
樓梯都不可以放東西喔
No escape ladder is not the one for our employees
都不可以逃生梯不是我們各位員工的那個
life-saving route
保命的路線
If you think the thing is very small, put it away for a while. If you want to
你覺得那個東西很小暫放一下那個人要報廢也暫放一下那個誰拆下來的也暫放一下他就堆滿了
So this is strictly prohibited
所以這個都是嚴格禁止
If you are renting
如果你是租房子的話
renting or you are the landlord
租房子或者是你是房東
the landlord
房東那個
If you rent a house to someone else, please help install this police device
租房子給別人的請你都幫忙裝一下這個住警器
Kaohsiung City has this self-government ordinance.
高雄市有這個自治條例如果你是租房子你可以要求
Just ask them to do it for you
直接要求他們幫你裝
all ok
都是ok的
then we today
那我們今天
safety and fire
安全跟消防的
Okay, let's talk about this first
好我們就先講到這邊
well thank you all
好好謝謝大家